<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacking on Teopeurt&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.teopeurt.com/categories/hacking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hacking on Teopeurt&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 10:05:50 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.teopeurt.com/categories/hacking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>All about the narrative</title>
      <link>http://blog.teopeurt.com/post/all-about-the-narrative/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 10:05:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.teopeurt.com/post/all-about-the-narrative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having the been to a few hackathons, I have witnessed the somewhat explosive fame of a few entrants. Beyond what they have built - most people build really awesome things - I have noticed a similarity to those who go on family..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its really all about the narrative, the ability to put in words ( and stir the emotional space) with alluring pictures and anecdotes. To break into the field, you have to have a good combination of telling a good story. These guys are good engineers, but beyond being great at what they do, they are excellent orators and public speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how do we as mere mortals get to this stage? Well beyond attending hackathons which are not suitable for everyone - especially with a family. I suggest going to meet-ups and presenting on a topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set a target to do as many speaking engagements as possible - just like coding the more you do, the better you get.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do a monthly review and assessment of your progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write every-day, thoughts and critics and what you have read. Do not necessarily make it public, journals have been a staple of our engineering diet for eons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do tutorials and training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Profit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, a lesson is nothing without exercise and practice, so go forth and multiply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This helps to build your narrative skills, as it breaks the anxiety barrier and lets you explore your creativity, thereby making a the world a better place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://blog.teopeurt.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 17:30:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.teopeurt.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An opinionated polyglot, I do data, I do software, I do open-source, I love building
distributed, connected services, with mobiles.
development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sometimes teach Python using the Raspberry PI as a tool for pre-teen, teenagers and young adult from disadvantage backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my past life I used to work with software in high performance cars
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.astonmartin.com/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jaguar.com/gb/en/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bmw.com/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;,
racing cars &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mclaren.com/home/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, regular cars
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ford.co.uk/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also tried to do something totally different in
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computational_finance&#34;&gt;Computational Finance&lt;/a&gt;,
realised that most of the theory was based on dodgy application of
Physics, so decided do my own research into analysing risk
and capital markets - similar in vein to
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-behavior-Markets-Benoit-Mandelbrot/dp/0465043550&#34;&gt;Mandelbroit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also once tried to build a self-sustaining, self-healing network using &lt;a href=&#34;http://villagetelco.org&#34;&gt;Village Telco&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>http://blog.teopeurt.com/2014/04/24/raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.teopeurt.com/2014/04/24/raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you may or may not know - I run &lt;a href=&#34;http://pigstycoders.com&#34;&gt;PigstyCoders&lt;/a&gt;. It is a small yet global boutique with clients across 4 continents and 10 countries. We love and are active in the  open-source community and give back whenever possible, either through hackathons, workshops and giveaways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have always had a passion for Africa and it&amp;rsquo;s potential and I think Africa is the next frontier in the digital evolution, hence why  are doing our best to enable local expertise, through workshops and talks. We don&amp;rsquo;t just believe in copying over products from Europe and USA - but using our expertise to tailor the approach to the continent, especially those at the BOP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sounds like a crazy plan but we are planning in giving away 100 Raspberry Pi&amp;rsquo;s across 10 African cities. Unlike other projects - this is not just a pump and dump mission. We are doing local workshops - backed with a live forum support and on-going discussion to help develop their skills further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who knows what will happen - just like open-source software - we just want to put this out there and see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Git Arsenal</title>
      <link>http://blog.teopeurt.com/2014/03/09/my-git-arsenal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.teopeurt.com/2014/03/09/my-git-arsenal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a huge fan of &lt;a href=&#34;http://git-scm.com/&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; and have been for many years. I tend to go through a lot of developer machines and thus will need to set up my dev environment really quickly - I only use Linux or Apple&amp;rsquo;s Mac so a shell script normally works for me. Two invaluable tools I have come to love over the years is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sourcetreeapp.com/&#34;&gt;SourceTree&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.perforce.com/product/components/perforce-visual-merge-and-diff-tools&#34;&gt;P4Merge&lt;/a&gt; by Perforce. As an aside Perforce is actually a proprietary version control system used in Enterprise but P4Merge is a free tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things everyone encounters when using Git are merge conflicts and this is where a visual tool is invaluable. I hate having to learn a new tool as my attention span is very limited and thus P4Merge does it for me. YMMV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sourcetree was an application originally developed for Mac OS X but was since acquired by Atlassian - owners of Bitbucket - so it has very good integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Git itself has a major learning curve but the investment is very much worth it. My advice is to take baby steps and don&amp;rsquo;t try to get into the holy wars about branching models etc - e.g whether &lt;a href=&#34;http://nvie.com/posts/a-successful-git-branching-model/&#34;&gt;git-flow&lt;/a&gt; is good for you or not.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails - Efficiency in Production</title>
      <link>http://blog.teopeurt.com/2012/09/04/rails-efficiency-in-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.teopeurt.com/2012/09/04/rails-efficiency-in-production/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rails Asset Pipeline - rails book&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Efficiency in Production&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best things about the asset pipeline is that it automatically results in assets that are optimized to be efficient in a production application.
Traditional methods for organizing CSS and JavaScript involve splitting functionality into separate files and using nice formatting (with lots of indentation). While convenient for the programmer, this is inefficient in production; including multiple full-sized files can significantly slow page-load times (one of the most important factors affecting the quality of the user experience). With the asset pipeline, in production all the application stylesheets get rolled into one CSS file (application.css), all the application JavaScript code gets rolled into one JavaScript file (javascripts.js), and all such files (including those in lib/assets and vendor/assets) are minified to remove the unnecessary whitespace that bloats file size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, we get the best of both worlds: multiple nicely formatted files for programmer convenience, with single optimized files in production.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNS Service Providers</title>
      <link>http://blog.teopeurt.com/2012/09/03/dns-service-providers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.teopeurt.com/2012/09/03/dns-service-providers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2010/12/06/announcing-amazon-route-53-dns-service/&#34;&gt;http://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2010/12/06/announcing-amazon-route-53-dns-service/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dnsimple.com/domains/new&#34;&gt;https://dnsimple.com/domains/new&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nettica.com/Prices/Default.aspx&#34;&gt;http://www.nettica.com/Prices/Default.aspx&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dnsmadeeasy.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.dnsmadeeasy.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My features
Aname, CName, DynamicDNS, API, Cheap / 10s - 100s of domains, TTL (not that these are respected)
setup, docs,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do these Compare?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;background:b916e23542b710bc00816e34b241a592&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always used Linode DNS manager, but not suitable for everything - especially A-Name&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making an EPUB Reader for Cocoa</title>
      <link>http://blog.teopeurt.com/2012/09/03/making-an-epub-reader-for-cocoa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.teopeurt.com/2012/09/03/making-an-epub-reader-for-cocoa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1388467/reading-epub-format&#34;&gt;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1388467/reading-epub-format&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The EPUB format brings together a bunch of different specifications / formats:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;one to say what the content of the book should look like (a subset of XHTML 1.1 + CSS)
one to define a &amp;ldquo;manifest&amp;rdquo; that lists all of the files that make up that content (OPF, which is an XML file)
one to define how everything is packaged up (OEBPS: a zip file of everything in the manifest plus a few extra files)
The specs look a bit daunting but actually once you&amp;rsquo;ve got the basics (unzipping, parsing XML) down it&amp;rsquo;s not particularly difficult or complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll need to work out how to download the EPUB, to unzip it somewhere, to parse the manifest and then to display the relevant content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some pointers if you&amp;rsquo;re just starting out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;parse xml&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unzip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To display content just use a UIWebView for now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a high level step by step for your code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) create a view with a UIWebView&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) download the EPUB file&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) unzip it to a subdirectory in your app&amp;rsquo;s documents folder using the zip library, linked above&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) parse the XML file at META-INF/container.xml (if this file doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist the EPUB is invalid) using TBXML, linked above&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) In this XML, find the first &amp;ldquo;rootfile&amp;rdquo; with media-type application/oebps-package+xml. This is the OPF file for the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) parse the OPF file (also XML)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) now you need to know what the first chapter of the book is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) each &lt;item&gt; in the &lt;manifest&gt; element has an id and an href. Store these in an NSDictionary where the key is the id and the object is the href.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b) Look at the first &lt;itemref&gt; in the &lt;spine&gt;. It has an idref attribute which corresponds to one of the ids in (a). Look up that id in the NSDictionary and you&amp;rsquo;ll get an href.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;c) this is the the file of the first chapter to show the user. Work out what the full path is (hint: it&amp;rsquo;s wherever you unzipped the zip file to in (3) plus the base directory of the OPF file in (6))&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) create an NSURL using fileURLWithPath:, where the path is the full path from (7c). Load this request using the UIWebView you created in (1).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll need to implement forward / backward buttons or swipes or something so that users can move from one chapter to another. Use the &lt;spine&gt; to work out which file to show next - the &lt;itemrefs&gt; in the XML are in the order they should appear to the reader.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RBENV Keeping Things Local</title>
      <link>http://blog.teopeurt.com/2012/08/16/rben-keeping-things-local/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.teopeurt.com/2012/08/16/rben-keeping-things-local/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The benefits of keeping things local,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working across machines- I have 4 physical machines I use daily and countless servers dotted around the world, I can never remember the shell commands for any particular project so I created build scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always hated having to rebuild dev environments hence I loved RVM. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sstephenson/rbenv/&#34;&gt;RBENV&lt;/a&gt; came along and I fell in love. Used in conjunction with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://gembundler.com/&#34;&gt;Bundler&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;code&gt;--path&lt;/code&gt; option, one can get a pretty awesome build going that is isolated and local just to that directory!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>