<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Swagger on Teopeurt&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.teopeurt.com/categories/swagger/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Swagger on Teopeurt&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 17:17:42 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.teopeurt.com/categories/swagger/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Api</title>
      <link>http://blog.teopeurt.com/post/open-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 17:17:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.teopeurt.com/post/open-api/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I am pleased to learn that &lt;a href=&#34;http://swagger.io/&#34;&gt;Swagger&lt;/a&gt; has been adopted/donated to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://openapis.org/&#34;&gt;Open API Initiative&lt;/a&gt;, anyone who has worked with me on any project will know along with many &amp;ldquo;truths&amp;rdquo; I apply to any of my project, I always adopt an &amp;ldquo;API First Design&amp;rdquo; and use Swagger as a way to document the api. I find this approach works for cross-platform team and even remote ones as it enables back-end to get on with the task at hand without front-enders and mobile team hovering over&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommended this approach when initial architecture designs for &lt;a href=&#34;https://hiho.com&#34;&gt;HiHo&lt;/a&gt; were taking place and we ended up  utilising the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/metosin/ring-swagger&#34;&gt;Clojure Ring-Swagger&lt;/a&gt; from day -1. I am happy to say that this decision was validated with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.parse.com/announcements/moving-on/&#34;&gt;other option&lt;/a&gt; dying off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an avid Linux User for over 10 years, the real number lies just double that, but don&amp;rsquo;t ask my age! I am pleased to see that this initiative is supported and hosted by the ever present and exquisite &lt;a href=&#34;http://collabprojects.linuxfoundation.org/&#34;&gt;Linux Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently working on a short book/tutorial on best practises on an API first approach, as there are many decisions which will come to haunt you if you take the wrong path and I have been stung many times in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>