<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Teopeurt&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.teopeurt.com/categories/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Teopeurt&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 10:05:50 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.teopeurt.com/categories/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>All about the narrative</title>
      <link>http://blog.teopeurt.com/post/all-about-the-narrative/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 10:05:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.teopeurt.com/post/all-about-the-narrative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having the been to a few hackathons, I have witnessed the somewhat explosive fame of a few entrants. Beyond what they have built - most people build really awesome things - I have noticed a similarity to those who go on family..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its really all about the narrative, the ability to put in words ( and stir the emotional space) with alluring pictures and anecdotes. To break into the field, you have to have a good combination of telling a good story. These guys are good engineers, but beyond being great at what they do, they are excellent orators and public speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how do we as mere mortals get to this stage? Well beyond attending hackathons which are not suitable for everyone - especially with a family. I suggest going to meet-ups and presenting on a topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set a target to do as many speaking engagements as possible - just like coding the more you do, the better you get.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do a monthly review and assessment of your progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write every-day, thoughts and critics and what you have read. Do not necessarily make it public, journals have been a staple of our engineering diet for eons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do tutorials and training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Profit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, a lesson is nothing without exercise and practice, so go forth and multiply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This helps to build your narrative skills, as it breaks the anxiety barrier and lets you explore your creativity, thereby making a the world a better place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>