<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pi on Teopeurt&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.teopeurt.com/tags/pi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pi on Teopeurt&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.teopeurt.com/tags/pi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>http://blog.teopeurt.com/2014/04/24/raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.teopeurt.com/2014/04/24/raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you may or may not know - I run &lt;a href=&#34;http://pigstycoders.com&#34;&gt;PigstyCoders&lt;/a&gt;. It is a small yet global boutique with clients across 4 continents and 10 countries. We love and are active in the  open-source community and give back whenever possible, either through hackathons, workshops and giveaways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have always had a passion for Africa and it&amp;rsquo;s potential and I think Africa is the next frontier in the digital evolution, hence why  are doing our best to enable local expertise, through workshops and talks. We don&amp;rsquo;t just believe in copying over products from Europe and USA - but using our expertise to tailor the approach to the continent, especially those at the BOP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sounds like a crazy plan but we are planning in giving away 100 Raspberry Pi&amp;rsquo;s across 10 African cities. Unlike other projects - this is not just a pump and dump mission. We are doing local workshops - backed with a live forum support and on-going discussion to help develop their skills further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who knows what will happen - just like open-source software - we just want to put this out there and see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Development</title>
      <link>http://blog.teopeurt.com/2013/01/18/mobile-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.teopeurt.com/2013/01/18/mobile-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A workshop I gave on developing for Mobile and the strategy to take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script
    async class=&#34;speakerdeck-embed&#34;
    data-id=&#34;3b7469c043c60130f33f1231381d4ca8&#34;
    data-ratio=&#34;1.33333333333333&#34;
    src=&#34;//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js&#34;&gt;
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://speakerdeck.com/teopeurt/mobile-development-practical-introduction&#34;&gt;Mobile development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The deck gives some very basic introduction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>